[Music]
Welcome to a Power of the Lamb
Ministries live event. We are happy to
be here with you. for us. We're starting
our Sabbath with you this evening. So, I
don't know what part of the world you
are in. Maybe Sabbath has not come for
you yet. Uh but when it does come, happy
Sabbath. And maybe you're in the part of
the world that it's been for a while,
but we are just happy to be with you
here uh this evening. Yeah,
we got uh somebody's asking if this is a
sermon for tomorrow. No, no, no. This is
actually This is the power of the lamb.
This is the power of the lamb. This is
not living mana event. So
see power of the lamb. See see I don't
have my t-shirt message on. Tried to
dress a little different for power of
the lamb so you guys can tell the
difference. Um so yeah we we got a lot
to talk about tonight. Yes. And uh we're
glad you guys have joined in. So thank
you for starting your Sabbath with us.
Yeah. Yeah. We are just going to invite
you
um to invite others, share this link. Uh
let people know that we are live
and that uh we're going to be talking
tonight about some pretty important
things. Some very important things. Some
things that will be um that will be a a
cause for pause
and serious reflection.
So, um, tune in. Tune in tomorrow for
the Yeah. for the t-shirt message.
Um, so guys, go ahead and hit that share
button. Let people know that we're on
live. Um, invite, invite, invite. And by
the way, if you are not subscribed to
Power of the Lamb, That's right. YouTube
page. Make sure you subscribe. Please
subscribe. If you're subscribed to
Living Mana Church YouTube page, that's
great. Thank you. We appreciate that.
But um Power of the Lamb is a separate
ministry and entity. So if you're only
subscribed to Living Mana, um you won't
get Power of the Lamb notifications. So
because they're they're two separate
things. So please um just please
subscribe if you are visiting with us.
If you've have this is your first time
and or you've you've watched Power of
the Lamb events before, but you've still
never subscribed, please do that this
evening. Yeah. So guys, we're gonna jump
in because like I said, we've got a lot
to talk about and um thank you John
Coleman and like. Yeah. Subscribe and
like. Yeah. So,
um let's uh let's pray. Okay. And then
we're going to jump in. And and by the
way, tonight we're dealing with, if you
do not know, if you didn't see the uh
the post from Facebook or um any of our
other social media, we're going to be
talking about prophetic bloopers. We're
going to be talking about prophetic
bloopers and that is going to be the
segue to talk about some other things as
well. Um but uh so we're going to be
covering a a couple of different things
tonight. Uh but hopefully we'll be able
to we'll be able to to get it all done.
So yes, we're going to pray and uh then
we're going to jump in and my job is to
learn with all of you and to She has no
idea what I'm doing. I I really don't. I
mean I not no idea but just just
generally I know what we're talking
about and um my job is to again slow
everything down so that we all catch it.
Yeah. We know what's going on as like we
said four years ago as if a 10-year-old
like you're explaining to a 10-year-old.
Yep. So let's pray. Okay. And let's uh
let's jump in. Heavenly Father, we thank
you Lord for uh giving us this
opportunity Lord to uh just come before
your people. And we ask Lord that you
would just guide our words, guide our
thoughts. Pray Lord that those that are
listening, those that are watching and
that will watch Lord will just um Lord
take this message to heart. Please Lord
speak to your people is our prayer in
Jesus name. Amen. Amen. Amen. All
right. So um there's been a lot going on
in the Adventist world. Um has been. And
uh one of the big things that has
happened that has gotten a lot of people
talking and we're not talking about that
tonight, but um the departure of you
know, a well-known um Adventist person.
Um and you know, people were surprised,
people were shocked, people were
dismayed. Um and there's been a lot
going on with that, you know, just about
that that discussion. Mhm. And um I
think one of the things
that
really sticks out for me right now and I
think is it is important for us as a
people to understand is that uh we
really have to know what we believe.
Yes. And you c you can be in the church
for years and actually not be certain,
not be sure, or actually literally not
know what you believe and just kind and
you might be confident until you're
faced with something, right? Like you
feel like you're in the right place and
it it seems like it's true and you kind
of just go with the flow. And the first
time I think this is years ago that I
think I mentioned it to you um that I
could really see an issue um because I
mean you were and still are I mean
you're a pastor ordained pastor but when
we were in the brickandmortar church and
you did evangelistic series where I'm
sitting in the pew and I'm right there
with the other people I would always
tell you it's like it's like as if um
when it comes to prophecy and answering
questions it was just like uh Uh people
were in a days. Sometimes they would
repeat what was cliche. Yeah. But they
were like in a days. Not You could tell
there was a days like they're still not
really understanding. I mean they they
just know they're just repeating what
they've always heard. And then nobody
really checks in with anybody like, "Do
you really know this? Do you really
know?" You know, it's just and you just
go with the flow. Yeah. And that's what
that is across the board in Adventism.
And not not that it's everybody. No,
it's not everybody, but it's just
everywhere. Yeah. We can take for
granted what we believe to be true. And
um I know that for me, like my personal
journey coming into this church, first
of all, was a challenge
because I'm in the music industry and
you know, now I'm considering leaving
money and fame.
I'm glad you said that because I'm gonna
make a correction to what I said. People
like you who studied your way into the
church, you guys know the majority and
even then even the majority that you're
pretty good because you studied your way
in. Yeah. But then my kind of people,
fourth generation or just born into the
church, those are the m a lot of them
are dazed. Yeah. Yeah. Um not everybody.
Yeah. But a lot. Yeah. So, so I know for
me, like I said, studying and coming
into the church was one thing. Making a
decision to leave the music industry, to
leave everything that was on the table
for us, that took a lot of I better make
sure that that this is the right thing
for me. And it didn't take me long, you
guys. Like, six months of studying this
and I was like, there is no other truth.
There is no other way. Like, this is it.
And then when I came into the church, it
was like a whole new level of I got to
really know what I believe because, you
know, coming in from the hip-hop
industry and the way I would approach a
scripture, there were a lot of people
that were like, "Man, that is amazing.
How did you see that?" But then there
were other people who were like, "How'd
you get that?" And like people would
actually challenge me like, you know,
you're making stuff up and blah blah
blah. Mhm.
And I remember that that got me to the
point where I was like, you know what?
Whatever I believe,
whatever I'm preaching, I'm going to
have to be able to defend every point of
every sermon that I ever preach. And I
began to like approach my sermons that
way. So that should anyone ever come to
me and be like, "Well, how'd you get
this? Well, where'd you get that from?"
I had to because I was getting
it because I was approaching the
scriptures so differently and it it made
me dig even deeper than what I thought I
was already digging. Also, it when you
came in, your parents thought you were
absolutely crazy. Yeah. They thought you
were crazy for what you were teaching
and crazy to leave the music industry
for something that's crazy. So, you
wanted to to prove them wrong. Yeah. You
wanted your parents to understand it.
you dug really really deep and I don't
know throughout I remember like in our
well I don't know about our well yeah
earlier days in ministry I would I would
say do you remember this I'd say do you
have to use so many Bible text in your
sermon to prove the point I was like
can't you use less just okay so in my
early days I would use that is that
comes from that you're so thorough
you're going to
use you try to seal off any area where
people can come in might be able to be
like this is wrong Nope. I can teach you
like this. This is what my husband does.
Or and you guys witness it all the time.
Every every Sabbath you witness it. But
he he's in my mind I'm seeing you like
you're like I can teach you like this or
I can teach you like this. I can teach
you like this. But it's going to be the
same thing. I'm coming at all these
directions with all these scriptures to
teach you the same thing. Like you want
it to be Bible proof. Yeah. Yeah. Like
we say, Bible all day. Bible all day,
right? But Bible proof. Yeah. So, I
wanna I wanna um the reason I set the
stage for that is to prepare for this
quote that I'm about to read. So, we're
going to go to the screen. Let's go to
the screen. And
um we're going to be talking
tonight, prophetic bloopers. We're going
to be talking about the Pope's death.
We're going to talking about the UN in
prophecy
and how all of this relates to
Adventism.
So here's the first statement that um I
want you to see
here. It says, "It is not enough to have
good intentions. It is not enough to do
what a man thinks is right or what the
minister tells him is right. His soul
salvation is at stake and he should he
should search the scriptures for
himself.
However strong may be his convictions,
however confident he may be that the
minister knows what is truth, that is
not his foundation. He has a chart
pointing out every way mark on the
heavenward
journey and ought not to guess at
anything. ought not to guess at
anything.
Um we shouldn't be guessing at anything
or right guessing assuming or assuming
anything.
Um, Ellen White makes a statement where
she says, "Many of us think we know what
we
believe and then when we are actually
brought face to face with a challenge
and we're not around the people that we
depend upon, we will find that we cannot
explain intelligently what we believe
and why we believe it." Right?
That is
uh that's a troubling thought
that you can be an
Adventist and think you know what you
believe and then when tested on it when
asked to present Bible evidence for why
you believe what you believe many will
not be able to do it right are not able
to do it.
It doesn't matter how passionate you are
about what you believe.
Can you actually demonstrate it from the
Bible?
And and again, this sets the foundation
for what we're going to talk about
tonight. Everybody knows that the Pope
um pass passed away. He's dead. Mhm.
And
that
really causes a lot of trouble for a lot
of
people because there was so
many prophecies given of what this pope
was going to do. So, I'm going to ask
you, put a one in the chat if um if you
are um if you're an ad if you are an
Adventist who has heard that because
this was the first Jesuit pope that he
was certainly or most
certainly or most
definitely going to bring
in a National Sunday
just put a one in the chat if you heard
something along those lines or or
something like
um you know the
the this is according to Revelation
chapter 17
uh there are seven popes that are
supposed to uh or six popes one isn't
one is and the eighth one to come and
Pope Francis is that eighth one.
This is it. Look at all these
ones, guys. Is is is am is is my head
under the rock. Like I
never when you said you were going to do
this, I was like, have a lot of people
heard that. Is that real people? But I
guess I've seen all the ones. So, you
were right.
This is the last pope. because I never
focus I I I just never focus
on one pope. I mean because it's the
system of Catholicism. So why focus on
one pope that was never I guess that's
why I just didn't pay attention to and
all the ones are still coming in. All
the ones are still coming in. There was
so much speculation made about this pope
as there will be about the next pope.
Are you Are you all with me so far?
And what what Okay, Tiffany Britt is
with me. She's a two. Okay. Okay,
Tiffany. Me and you.
So, what does that say?
And there are a lot of Adventists that
that believe
this that were like, "Yeah, you know, it
it it's this pope, etc.
And it was like that for the pope
before.
And I think one of the problems because
now people are having
to bury, you know, like kind of
revamp what they had been saying.
And that's troubling, guys, because
we're not supposed to approach prophecy
like this.
I had people emailing me like, you know,
this is the eighth pope um and the one
that before, you know, continue the
short space, you know, all kinds of
things. All kinds of things. And
um I want to say the first thing I'm I'm
going to say, the first thing I'm going
to say
is as Nerky just said, too much
speculation. Mhm.
We feed off of speculation.
Mhm. And that ought not to be so.
Um,
we talk so much about the
pope. I I think it's to the point where
many of us know more about the moves of
pope of the pope than we do about the
moves of Jesus.
we know more about the
Pope and we're focused more on the Pope
than we are on Jesus.
But we've talked about this before and
you've you've mentioned it in
presentations and sermons before.
Um
it's because if if if when people are
learning about the prophecies and and
they they take away from our
evangelistic series, you know, they take
away many things, but one thing that
they take away is um you know, the
position of who the Catholic Church is
and the leader and that type of thing.
So they focus on on that. And so it's
not
um I mean it's just I I don't want to
say it's like it's it's the way that I
feel like we present and teach prophecy
that causes it's not like we're teaching
the truth but I think the emphasis is in
the wrong place because it makes people
focus just on that. I was just having a
discussion a couple weeks ago about this
with a young adult. I'm gonna I'm gonna
show you something.
Um, let's go. Let me see
here. All right. Let's go to the screen.
And, um, I want you to check this
out. So, uh, here are the four
popes
that lived
during Ellen White's life. Right? So,
you have Pope Gregory the 16th. Um he
died in
1846. Um you have uh Pope Pas I 9th and
he was from 1846 to to uh
1878. And then Leo I 13th, he was from
1878 to 1903. And then Pope Pius I 10th,
he was from 1903 to
1914. Now I got a question for you. Test
question. How many times do you think
Ellen White mentioned these popes by
name? What do you
think? What do you think? Put some
numbers in the chat for me and just just
take a
guess. Just take a guess. I'm going to
start with Pope Pas the
16th. Uh, I'm sorry, Gregory the
16th. If you do a search, so I I
actually screenshot screen screenshotted
the search. She mentioned Pope
Gregory the
16th
once. Once. And it's in one book, The
Great Controversy. And it's not even in
the body of the book, it's in the
appendix of the book.
Okay. What about
um Pope
Pas the
9th? That was more of you know after her
prophetic role began. So you can look
and see Pope Pas the 9th. You can see in
the search engine she mentions him five
times. Five times. And again, all five
times are I'm sorry, four times are in
the book, The Great Controversy. And of
those four times, all of them are again
in the back of the book, The Appendings.
You would almost think,
"What was the matter with her?" Did she
not know that she should be calling out
these popes and talking about everything
they're doing? So, I want you to see
here. Let me let me go to the next one.
Here is Pope Leo I 13th from 1878 to
1903. Again, a search of Pope Leo the
13th. I got the wrong slide up there,
but I think she mentioned, let's
see, is that it? Yep, there it is. Four
times.
Four times she mentioned Leo the 13th.
And the last
one, this would be uh pious the
10th. That number
is one
time. One time. Now, I'm going to ask
y'all a question. I want you to um I
want you to put in the chat. I just want
to see some of your responses so far.
What do you think about what you just
saw? Is anybody
surprised? And maybe surprised in a good
way or maybe surprised in a bad way.
How many of you how many of you are like
wait a minute like compare what what
happens in you know on a lot of in a lot
of ministries today, right? How often
have you heard the name Pope Francis did
this, Pope Francis did
that? I want you to note the difference,
you guys.
The
prophet spent very little time
talking about these individual popes.
When she mentions them, it's they wrote
this encyclical and said this about this
particular doctrine, said this about
that particular doctrine.
But the issue was not the pope as an
individual, right? We have never been
caught up on the pope as an individual.
It's about the position. The position,
the system. And I think what has
happened today is that we have become so
um caught
up in which pope, which pope, which
pope, what's the pope doing now that
we're focusing more on him than we are
of Jesus.
Yes. Um if you look if you were to look
at uh let's say the
pioneers of the same time. So let's go
back to the screen.
And and so I did the same search for the
pioneers. And what you'll see here is
that for one of these popes, Pope Pius I
10th, the pioneer writings. So that's
the periodicals, the articles, they
mentioned Pope Pis the 10th 17
times. 17 times.
In another one, Leo the 13th, he is
mentioned
358 times. Now, you might think, "Oh,
okay. There you go. 358 times,
guys. Here's what I want you to see
here." So, let's just go back. I'mma
show you a slide
here. Uh,
okay. Here we
go. So, um, the websites are are below,
right? They're an adventist review. Uh
by the 1880s, track societies across the
world were distributing distributing
close to five million pages of material
a
year a year through this correspondence
method resulting in many converts as
produced by the traditional evangelistic
uh preaching series. Uh by 1844 the
Millerite the Millerites when the
Millerites wrongly expected the second
coming of Christ early believers had
already distributed an astonishing 8
million pieces of literature. Let me ask
you a
question. If you were to take 358
mentions of a particular
pope and compare that to the number of
articles, written words, pages, do you
understand how minuscule of a number
that is? Yeah.
You thought that 358. Well, see, there
you go, pastor. No, no, no. It's not a
lot. It's not a lot at all.
They were not in the habit of watching
the present pope and trying to see
everything that he was doing because it
wasn't about the pos. It wasn't about
the individual. It was about the
position and it was about a much larger
system. We understand that. But we seem
to have lost that today because we know
that if we put up a video about the
pope, everybody's going to watch. Mhm.
We know that if we talk about the pope,
everybody's going to be like, "Oh man,
you staying on top of
things." But is that actually
backfiring? I suggest it is you
guys. I suggest
that we are becoming
so our record is getting really bad
and there is no need for that because we
ought not to be guessing at anything.
When you say our some people the people
who who focus right on on the pope in
this way I put emphasis there their
record is bad. Yeah. So I'm saying our
because I'm just putting us all in the
lump. Okay. Right. Putting us all in
there. Um let me go back to the screen
and I want you to see
this.
Um here we go. So there are many in the
church who take it for granted that they
understand what they believe. But until
controversy arises, they do not know
their own weakness.
When separated from those of like faith
and compelled to stand singly and alone
to explain their belief, they will be
surprised to see how confused are their
ideas of what they had accepted as
truth.
Certain it is that there has been among
us a departure from the living God and a
turning to men putting human wisdom in
the place of divine. Now notice what she
says next. God will arouse his people if
other means fail. Heresies will come in
among them which will sift them
separating the chaff from the
wheat. The Lord calls upon all who
believe his word to awake out of sleep.
Precious light has come appropriate for
this time. It is Bible truth showing the
perils that are right upon us. The light
should lead us to a diligent study of
the scriptures and a most critical
examination of the positions we hold.
I I think you guys I genuinely genuinely
believe in my
heart that we have allowed so much chaff
cha chaff to come in to our teachings
that it is becoming difficult to
distinguish between what is actually
wheat, what we actually believe as a
church, right? And what is chaff. what
what has
been assumed as Bible truth and actually
is not
and it's a very it's a very
serious question. It's a very serious
thing because how many of us strongly
believe something that we have no
evidence for in the scriptures?
The first thing I want to I want to
recap is that we need to be watching
Jesus more than we're watching the Pope.
Amen. We need to be watching Jesus more
than we're watching the Pope.
The second thing I want to I want to
emphasize is what I believe is a growing
ignorance or lack of understanding of
the Bible amongst God's people.
Just because someone is saying something
with conviction doesn't mean that it's
true, right? Doesn't mean that it's
accurate. Doesn't mean that it is
biblical.
Um I believe that we we are we are
eating now what I'm calling prophecy
stew. So what do y'all think I mean when
I say prophecy stew?
Well, with a stew you put a lot of
different ingredients. just throw stuff
in there. Yeah. And just make it all all
prophecy. And you try to make it all
taste good. And you you make it taste
good. You try to make it taste good. And
guess what? It might taste
good. It might taste
good. But the question for you is, is it
good? You know the saying, sometimes
things that taste good are not good for
you, right? Yes.
The things that sometimes taste the best
are often the things that have a lot of
sugar in it, a lot of
sweets. And what's happening is we're
now I I everything becomes prophecy,
that's prophecy, stew. And what you have
happening is, and and trust me, you
guys, I'm not calling out, you know, I
think ministries need to be held
accountable for putting stuff out there
that is
sweet and having the people eat it up
and then when those things don't happen,
yes, potluck, prophecy, potluck. When
things don't happen, they just go on,
step away as if nothing was ever said.
They're quiet for a while and then
another one will No, we're just going to
we're just going to move to a new Yeah.
It's a short while. They're they're
they're quiet on they don't ever go back
and correct their mistake because to to
say it was a mistake then or what will
the people say?
Mhm.
The prophecy stew is getting really,
really, really, really crazy.
To the point where, you know, people are
like, "Well, what if Pope Francis
resurrects?"
Did somebody say that? If he resurrects,
you're kidding, right? I'm
saying like there are some people who
thought Pope the Pope wasn't going to
die. This was going to be it. So, what
I'm saying is I see what you're saying.
How Yeah. How far do we go?
when we ought not to be guessing at
anything. Itching ears, Kevin. Itching
ears. Yeah. We want the spicy. You know
why? And it's sad, y'all. Here's what's
so sad. We don't think Jesus draws.
And in our church, listen to me now. In
our church,
Jesus does not draw.
You want to test me on that? Okay.
Clarify. Clarify. Hold on. Let me let
let me not for everyone. I'm not talking
about for everyone. That's what I was
saying. In certain
uh in certain circles spaces Jesus does
not draw, right? And and you can tell
simply by just go online, go on social
media, look at what gets the most
uh uh clicks, the most view. do
something about Jesus and see how many
Adventists are like, "Oh, man. I watched
this powerful sermon on
prayer." Oh, it was
amazing. 100,000
views. Why prayer is important. No, no,
no, not not Adventist. That's that's
precious truth. What we need is present
truth.
Jesus doesn't draw. And that's a sad
commentary. you
guys. Yes. SDA dopamine. We need the
next hit. We need the next prophetic
hit. And so if it's not if it's not we
we we got we have to find something that
we can say see and this is a fulfillment
of prophecy. And beloved when everything
is a fulfillment of prophecy then
nothing is a fulfillment of prophecy. We
begin to lose our prophetic edge our
prophetic importance. It is better to be
silent and speak when appropriate than
to be always speaking and always this is
prophecy, this is prophecy, this is
prophecy because not we're just looking
for stuff and you know climate change
was definitely going to bring in the
Sunday law. Remember there's Yeah. Yeah.
And there's still time COP 26 and COP 27
and and all these different things.
Everything becomes prophecy. What
happened in in what hap everything
becomes prophecy.
Things that have little to no connection
to prophecy become prophecy because we
want it to be prophecy. I've talked
about this, I don't know here, but I've
talked about it on church uh during a
Sabbath school before that, you know, I
I like to say that Adventists are
probably the most anxious people. Um
They're afraid. There's fear. All
because, you know, God said remember and
so we're just like, "Okay, we can't
forget. We can't forget." And there's
just so much anxiety. And he doesn't
want us to have anxiety at all. No. Um,
and not everybody does. But you know
what? No. But that there's a lot of
fear. There's a lot of fear.
And when we're motivated by fear because
we're looking at the beasts and the
dragon and and we're not and we're
looking at the pope and we're not
looking at Jesus. Right. And that's what
I was going to say. When you're looking
at Jesus, you don't God doesn't give us
the spirit of fear. That's right. So
when we're when we have all that fear,
everything, you know, everything always
has to be you're afraid. Like everything
has to be coming around the corner. Oh,
that's a you're watching out. That is
that is like you're always scared. So
you're always on alert because you're
anxious and you're afraid of fear. You
know, you're afraid and that's a sad
commentary. And we don't want to
approach God's word with the spirit of
fear. Mhm. But but but that's what
happens. Yes. We have to look out at
everything, you know, look for
everything that's happening. The and the
thing that we should be looking at
prophetically speaking, it it kind of
goes by the wayside now because now
we're looking at, you know, this is
prophecy and that is prophecy and
and
it's it's prophetic stew. It's prophetic
stew. So, I'm going to give an example.
I'm going to give a demonstration to
you. And now you're going to be like,
"Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Hold on,
pastor." So, I asked a question. I asked
a question because this is something
that that I hear a lot. So, I was on
Facebook the other day and I asked a
question. I said, um, where is the
United Nations in Bible prophecy? We're
talking about prophecy stew, right?
We're talking about just dumping stuff
in the pot. Dumping stuff in the pot,
ingredients in the pot, and then making
it all part of the Adventist message,
making it all a part of the three angels
messages. Everything is not the three
angels messages. There are prophetic
scenarios that don't belong to us.
But when we approach prophecy in this
prophecy stew type of way, we start
putting anything in the pot. And again,
everything anything becomes prophecy.
And that's what we see happening in
Adventism right now. And let me tell
you, it might be it might be adrenaline
for a while, right? But when that hit
passes and you're like, I got to go on
to the ne I got to go on to the next
hit. And sometimes you don't want the
hit to die. So you got to keep that
thing alive because you think this is
prophecy. And now you are doing
everything in your power to try to prove
that something is prophecy. keeping it
alive because it is that dopamine that
SDA
dopamine that if we don't have we're
like well how am I gonna how am I going
to stay excited about
what Jesus doesn't doesn't fulfill that
I love for many people it doesn't I love
the analogy like Dr. White and I just
did did two programs on mental health
Mondays on um on addiction. And that's
the problem. Like we're supposed to get
dopamine, but it's supposed to be
balanced and not all the time back to
back to back. That's how you become an
addict. So like you're becoming prophecy
addicts because it's like you're you're
not supposed to you're not supposed to
get it all the time. It's supposed to be
balanced. You're supposed it's a whole
thing. But and that's and that's not
what's happening. And and look y'all,
I'm a prophecy addict.
I I make y'all hear me talk about
prophecy and I'm always seeking to
balance it with Jesus. Now, if you
disagree with that, that's maybe you're
right. But what I'm telling you is my
intention say you're an addict. I'm an
addict. I'm an addict to Jesus. I'm an
addict to prophecy. I love these things.
You love and you love teaching it. Yes.
You don't you don't love What you don't
love is u I got to have prophecy no
matter what. There's a difference,
right? Yeah. You don't go to the
conspiracy to make That's what I'm
saying. You don't put 10 on two. I just
learned that this week, Brother Terry,
when he was saying 10 on 10 on two, you
see what I'm saying? Like, you don't try
to You're not creating prophecy for the
sake of I got to have a hit. Exactly.
Because So, I'm making everything be
prophecy now. And look what the Pope
just did over there. That's prophetic.
And look at what just happened here.
That's prophetic. And look at what our
government is doing. That's prophetic.
There are prophetic things. But when we
make everything prophecy
when it's time to pay attention to
something, we don't. And can Okay. Well,
there's two things, but um and I'm
coming to my question. Okay. Go ahead.
So, our basic prophecy, which I I I
hated to just call it basic because it's
not basic. But the prophecy that we know
is sufficient is so rich, powerful, and
so pro prophetic that we don't need to
add anything. We don't need to add
seasoning. Are you getting bored with
it? If you're getting bored with it, I'm
sorry because you don't need to add
anything to it. And so then when you do
what you were just when you're always
doing what you were just sharing, um
it's like when something really is
happening that we should be paying
attention to. I'm gonna I'm gonna I'm
gonna go here with Project
2025. You were talking about it almost
two years before
many many people in the church were
talking about it. a lot and many people
didn't start talking about till after it
was really too and are still hesitant to
talk about it. Right? So what I'm saying
is like people weren't paying attention
to that. You see how like the enemy was
like they were paying attention to to
the climate change and to whatever. But
that that just kind of slipped up and
they just were not a lot of people were
not paying attention or don't even worry
about it. It's that I heard from you. I
heard that from from so I'm just saying
like that's what happens when you're
always um you know talking about things
that are not actually prophetical and
then when something actually and I'm not
saying like project 2025 is it's
something to that we should have been
paying attention to that we should have
been watching because it actually um was
something that could take our religious
liberties away. Yep. Yep. So, um, I want
you all to I'm gonna ask you a
question. And here's a question that I
asked on my on my after I was thinking
these things. I was like, I'm gonna ask
a question on Facebook and I'm going to
see what kind of response I get. So, the
question was, hey guys, where is where
do we get that the United Nations is a
part of the three angels messages? That
the United Nations being evil, being
bad, being a a a
being a part of the forces that are
going to bring about Sunday law. Where
do we get that in the Bible? And so my
question was, I just want Bible,
right? I just want
Bible. And
um let me do something here. I'm going
to I'm going to skip a couple slides.
I'm gonna I'm just going to share with
you some of the
responses. Um hold on. Don't go to the
screen yet.
Okay. Um,
so here, let's let's
uh here we go. Okay. So, I've blotted
out all the names. Um, and you know
what? I'm not even going to do that. Uh,
don't don't show my slides because
people might look at the slides and then
go back to my slide and see the name of
the person that that said whatever. But
I'm just going to kind of read excerpts
from some slides. Okay. Um, that way I
can protect everybody's identity and I'm
not trying to call anybody out. Okay. Um
so
um one person believes that you know
that the UN is in Revelation chapter
18 that it's talking about the you know
the the uh kings of the earth that's
what represents the UN. Now by the way
remember my question was like we know
that the papacy is in the Bible. We know
that America is in the Bible. What about
the UN? Now, I got to tell you this. The
response to this question was almost
like now we know Pastor M is going off
his rocker because how are you asking a
question? Where is the United Nations in
the Bible? Everybody we all know what do
you know how I was lost on that one. How
much
I know. So,
the interesting thing
was that of all the responses I was
getting, it was almost like, "Well,
don't you know it's in the
Bible?" I had one person
um say say to me, "This is lack of
wisdom, dear Ivor."
And then they go on to explain why the
UN you know the UN is a is
a is a branch of the of the papacy and
um you know other verses and then you
know so much of my studying has like
made me lose my mind. So that was one
response, you know, a couple other
responses like this, like what are you
serious? Are you actually asking? But no
one was providing an actual study of of
a Bible verse that said here, here we
get the papacy this way. We get apostate
Protestantism this way, right? And
here's where we
see the United Nations as an
organization, the organization of the
United Nations.
And so it it's this taking for granted
that yeah, everybody knows the United
Nations is evil. And if it's evil, it's
a part of Bible
prophecy. I mean, we can't tell you
where exactly in the Bible it is, but we
know it's there. I mean, it's obvious.
Look at all the books that have been
written. A and
so it re it began to reveal the very
thing that I'm that I'm saying here is
that many of us drop stuff into the into
the prophecy stew. M and when you stew
something, you know, like the flavor
begins to share. So you don't
necessarily know when you're eating, you
know, one thing versus another because
the flavors just blend. That's what a
stew
is. If we're dropping stuff in the three
angels pot that doesn't belong in the
three angels pot and claiming that it's
that that it's a three it's part of the
three angels messages, you guys, we are
in danger. And I I'm saying that I'm
trying to, you know, not get wor. I'm
trying to say it in as calm a way as I
can.
But you don't say you're in danger very
calmly. People don't say when somebody's
in danger, you you're not calm. You're
not supposed to be calm. You're not
supposed to be calm. Give an alarm. So,
Revelation 17 is given, oh, the 10
kings, that's the United Nations. Um, no
one mentioned a particular chapter,
which they should have, but they're
like, "Well, there's something that's
stopping them from saying, well, it's
that chapter." But I'm going to show you
something, okay? How many of you have
ever seen Get ready. Get ready for this,
y'all. When I talk about step away from
Prophecy Stew and just eat the undiluted
word of God, um, let me show you
something.
So in Daniel chapter 2 we know that we
have you know the image Babylon and then
meersia and then Greece and then Rome
and then the 10 toes uh symbolize uh the
dividing of Rome and then the papacy. So
our view is what we call historicism.
Right? There's an unconnected line of
prophecy that goes from Babylon all the
way to the rise of the papacy.
But our evangelical friends do not share
that view. What you're looking at on the
screen right now might confuse you. But
let me show you what it is. So in this
version of Daniel chapter 2, you have
Babylon, right? Meo Persia, Greece, then
Rome, and then I want you to note what
happens after the fall of Rome in 476
AD. It's almost like a
gap is
introduced. Did y'all hear what I just
said? A gap is
introduced. There is a gap between Rome
and the 10 toes of ir of iron and clay.
Mhm. The reason that that gap is there
is that they they skip past the breaking
down of the ancient Roman Empire. They
skip past the little horn. And what they
do instead is they say that these 10
toes are yet future.
Therefore, this will be a revived Roman
Empire.
That is what we call futurism. Right?
That is what we call dispensationalism.
So, it's the gap theory. So, you know,
for those of you that are familiar with
the the We as Adventists don't believe
that. No, we don't. I know.
But wait a minute. How did that get in
the pot, though? Right. Exactly. How did
that get in the pot? That shouldn't have
been put put in the pot. Now, we don't
say a revived Roman Empire, right? But
here's what we are saying because it's
almost the same thing. Let me show you.
Let me show you. Let's go back. Here's
another image.
Same
thing different different image but I
want you to note again here you have
Egypt then Assyria and those are not
part of the image according to this this
picture but then you have Babylon Persia
Greece Rome and then for the toes of
iron and clay you have Britain and the
USA and then note what you have
next you have the League of
Nations which was what was existing and
then you know to try to stop a world war
from happening. World War I happened and
after that it dissolved and after that
became the United Nations.
This image is teaching that the toes of
iron and clay are the United Nations.
Again, dispensationalism, futurism. This
is we skip past the fall of Rome or the
the the disintegration of Rome into the
barbarian tribes. We skip past the
papacy and we go to something in the
future, the United Nations. Now, I'm
going to I'm I want to take a guess. I
want you to take a guess. Who is this
second chart from? Anyone know what
denomination holds or is the first
because this is a very old chart. Mhm.
What denomination is it
that teaches that the 10 toes are the
United Nations and the League of Nations
and also Britain and USA?
What denomination?
Yep. While you're guessing, let's go
back to the screen. Let's go back to the
screen. I'm going to show you another
chart yet again. Here's another one.
Babylon, Meopersa, Greece, Rome, and
again look at this.
The European
Union. The European Union. The European
Union is the 10 toes.
So, I'm going to show you where this
comes from. Yes, you have it right
there.
Let's see.
Wow. This is from a website called Got
Questions. And you guys may know that
website. It's not an Adventist website,
but it's a very well-known website. A
lot of people go to it, you know, when
they have questions. And so, here's one
of the questions they ask. Uh, the
question was about the 10 the 10 the 10
toes.
Here's what they say. A one world or
global government is predicted in Daniel
and Revelation. It will come after the
rise of a confederation of 10 nations or
regions. Please note this y'all. It will
it will
come after the rise of a confederation
of 10 nations or regions. What is
quoted? Revelation 13:1, Daniel
7:16-24, and Daniel
2:41-42. Listen to what it goes on to
say. One member of the confederate of
the confederation will displace three of
the other members, subdue the others,
and rule over all led by the satanic
empowered antichrist. It is this
confederation of 10 nations that is most
often connected with the United
Nations. Let me read one more. Same
website. Another prophecy that some
people connect with the United Nations
is found in Revelation 17:18. There
Babylon the Great or the of
Babylon is condemned. The first mention
of Babel is in Genesis 11, the story of
the Tower of Babel. The building of the
tower was mankind's first attempt at
world government in defiance of God.
Babylon the Great in the end times is a
similar cong conglomeration of
nations attempting to unite against God.
Now beloved, we know that that's wrong.
We know that Babylon is not a
conglomeration of nations. It's a
conglomeration of churches.
But they believe it's a conglomeration
of nations attempting to unite against
God. This fact, the fact that this evil
world system is called a mystery is
called a mystery in Revelation 17:15
indicates that we do not yet know all
the details. So this is from the same
question.
They
believe according to Daniel 2 that the
little horn I'm sorry not the little
horn that uh the 10 kingdoms is the
United
Nations. Now evangelicals didn't start
this. Let me really show you where this
comes from. Let's go back to the screen.
And one of you got this right. A lot.
No, several people. Okay. Several of you
got this right. jw.org or Jehovah's
Witnesses mercy. The scarlet colored
beast described in Revelation chapter 17
is a symbol of the organization whose
purpose is to unite and represent the
nations of the world. It first existed
as a League of Nations and is now the
United Nations, a political entity. Let
me ask you a question, guys. When did we
when did we
adopt Jehovah's Witness teaching on
prophecy? When did that happen? Anyone?
Somebody tell me. Yeah. How did we adopt
their view of the United Nations?
Because I'll tell you in my in my post I
was getting Revelation chapter 17.
Mercy.
Really? Revelation time. Pastor, I see
you. Oh, good to see you, sir. Pastor
Jose, good to see you, Pastor Jose. You
You've thrown me off. Our dear friend.
Now, now, now I can't think. I can
think. It's good to see you, man.
Okay. So,
so when did this get into the pot?
Because most people think this was this
is Adventist. They're like, "Don't you
know, pastor?" Listen, y'all. I'm going
to show you. I'm going to show you.
Let's see if I got this here.
Okay, let's go to the screen. Let's go
to the screen and I'm going to play a
video for you. It's a short video, but I
need you to listen carefully. Go ahead.
You're listening to the critical
thought, where we challenge our
listeners to use critical thinking when
examining the teachings of Jehovah's
Witnesses. Hi, this is Daniel. This is
JT. And the purpose of this video is to
talk to you about the Jehovah's
Witnesses and the United Nations things
you should know. Yeah, JT. So, let's
talk. All right. So, what should our
people know about the Jehovah's
Witnesses and the United Nations? What
what did for some This is going to sound
obscure. What do the United Nations and
the Jehovah's Witnesses have to do with
one another? Yeah. Uh well, you kind of
like roll you got to roll the clock back
a little bit. uh when the what was known
as the League of Nations after World War
I, they set government set up the League
of Nations. Uh Jehovah's Witnesses
jumped on it as soon as they set up and
and their basic position was very simple
that the League of Nation was a
counterfeit substitute kingdom for God's
kingdom. Okay, that was their that was
the position they took. As a result, any
religion, any religious denomination
that had any working relationship,
friendly relationship, whatever
relationship with the with the League of
Nations, they was sinning against God.
That was their basic position. Of
course, we know the years the League of
Nation collapsed and then they set up
what was called what we have today, the
United Nations. Once again, Jehovah's
Witnesses back in the 40s, they jumped
on it again. any religion that has any
connection, relationship, working
relationship with the United Nations,
they sinning against God. In fact, they
refer to it as going down to Egypt.
You're going to get help from Egypt
instead of relying on God. So, that was
their position. It was very clear.
Magazines after magazines, talks after
talk, every Jehovah's Witness knew this
until an article came out in a mag
Did you all hear that just now? Put a
one in the chat if you now
understand that Jehovah's
Witnesses were the very first ones
to prophetically identify the United
Nations as
a relig as a uh fulfillment of Bible
prophecy. Did they package it different?
Like I'm so surprised that that is where
it came from and that like and I'm going
to tell you how not even I mean yes that
we we would do that but even
evangelicals would do that. They're not
they're not repeating anything Jehovah
Witness say. Yeah. Nothing. Right. They
don't even know that that it comes from
Jehovah's Witnesses. Wow. But I'm going
to show you something. We're going to go
to our next slide. Let's see here.
All right. We're not find I'm surprised
at at Advent Adventist who are saying
that and I'm surprised at evangelical
I'm surprised anybody is saying what
Jehovah Jehovah witnesses are saying
because number one they think they're a
cult which
we're not which is an issue. Yeah. Yeah.
But um all right let me I don't know if
uh my team could get in and get this
slide. For some reason it's it's not
moving. Um and I want to go to the next
slide. of if you can get in and get that
change. But why while they working on
that? So
what we see here is that this is not of
Adventist origin. No. How did it get in
the pot? So let's go back. Okay, here we
go. Um, check this out, you guys. Let's
go to the next slide. M so in the
1970s um I'm sorry really in the
1950s and the 1960s
some evangelicals or Christians began
writing that the formation of the United
Nations was a global plot to basically
overthrow America
so that you know the world was into
globalism
And ultimately it this was going to be
an attack on America which is for
nationalism. America is the greatest
nation on the planet. And the other
nations we are the only thing stopping
this Satan from taking over the whole
globe. And so the United Nations became
the prophetic
symbol became the prophetic symbol to
represent all that is against American
Christianity. Now go to the screen.
Watch this. How many of you have ever
heard of a man by the name of Tim Lehei?
Yes. Yes. Tim Lehei. the left behind
guy, right? The left behind guy. Um
before you go on, can I just say one
thing because
um I don't know all this is doing for me
is like if going back to our series back
to the basics. Yep. Like if you
understood that that that the UN is not
the whirlwind. We take we we we take so
much for granted. Yeah. The UN is not
the UN is not what's going to convince
everybody. That's what I'm saying. So
why we don't have to focus on that.
My mind is very basic. It's not like as
deep as yours, but to me that is like so
basic. Like if you can just apply that
that simple understanding, you should
not be getting confused with this. Yeah.
Like the UN. And the thing is even in
prophecy, we know that even if there was
an entity that was going to try to
destroy Yes. Christianity, it's not
gonna it's not going to do it. Yeah.
Because the evangelical or you know the
religious right connected to the
Catholic Church. Yeah. And the whirlwind
is what's going to And really the
whirlwind really. True. So So here's the
thing. So Christianity is not going to
be taken over. Yeah. Or get it's not
going to get it's not that's not the
prophecy. Christianity is not it's not
going to go away. Yeah. But Christians
believe that. And so their enemy,
they're all they're afraid. Yeah. Their
enemy is secularism and globalism. Yes.
And that the UN, we got to get out of
the UN. We got to separate. That's
evangelical thinking. How did that get
in the pot?
How did Go back. Hold on. Watch this. Go
back and
look. We're going to do that. Actually,
I need to tell you what I Let just Hold
on. Let me show you something else. Let
me show you something
else. Um, let's go back to the screen
and I want you to watch this next video.
All right, y'all ready? Um, I'm going to
make sure that you guys can hear this. I
want to try to hear it myself. So, let's
go ahead and play the
video. While some may turn to the books
because of their interest in
Christianity, most will get more than
just a spiritual boost. The stories also
carry a distinctly political message.
That serpent has stood between us and
paradise ever since. In the books and
the film, the modern-day Antichrist is
the head of the United Nations. He gets
to that position with the help of
shadowy international financiers.
Nikolai, you know that's preposterous.
Do not lie to me. The casting of the
Antichrist as the head of the UN
reflects Leah's own personal suspicions.
Dear, do you know who you're dealing
with?
Do you?
Why did you choose the United Nations to
be the body that the Antichrist
essentially uses to take over with?
Well, he's going to establish a one
world government. That's one reason
Christians are suspicious of globalism.
They see it as maybe a precursor of
Antichrist. And I just use the United
Nations because it's a entity today that
people can understand. It may not be the
United Nations. It may be something
else. In fact, I wouldn't be surprised
in today's geopolitical situation where
the United Nations and the European
common market uh will gradually grow
together and join other countries of the
world uh against the United States, the
superpower and uh gradually they will
move their their center of government to
Iraq. An interesting thing in the Bible
is this is from your book or this is
what you're saying will happen. Well,
this what I'm saying will probably
happen that the capital of uh the
antichrist kingdom will be in Babylon.
All right. What will probably happen?
What will probably okay happen? Okay.
How did So this began with Jehovah's
Witnesses number one and and then it
moved into evangelicalism
mercy. And now so what happened is like
in the 60s the 70s and the 80s all of
these conspiracy books please don't
y'all don't get mad at me now. I'm just
I'm just telling you historically what
has
happened. I should have brought these
books with me because you know what?
When I came into Adventism, I don't know
how I got a hold of these books, but I
got a hold of these books. How many of
y'all remember those books
from the 90s? Well, I was reading them
in the 90s. So, the New World Order 666,
um, these white books, they were thick
books. So, they were all white and then
they would have the green. Yeah. The
allseeing eye, the Illuminati, the
allseeing eye. I still got them. Yep. I
thought I I'd swear I've seen them. And
I would read these books and I'd be like
yo that that you know me and my friends
yo and we didn't re actually when I read
these books I thought the guys writing
the books were advent I don't know why I
thought that but I was just like man
they they I mean they maybe not talking
about the sab because they're just
trying to you know but that's when you
were first when you were no that's when
you were in the music you guys used to
We were still in the music. Right.
Right. Right. Right. Yeah. And actually
those books were some of the books that
we were reading that like when we wrote
the song the mark of the beast. I was
going to say like it was still we had
just been learning about the Sabbath. We
were reading these books, right? Whole
series of them. Yes. Put a one in the
chat if y'all remember them. 666 was the
name of one book and the books just look
so scary. Right. It kind of reminded me
of Jan Marcus's book National Sunday
Law. So it was like Jan Marcus's book
National Sunday Law and then these other
books six which to me was just like man
this just takes it all the way deeper. I
didn't know they were not Adventist
books.
So, I'm just like, "Yeah, the builder
the Bilderbergs and the, you know, all
these things just
and it all just be the League of Nations
and the United Nations and yo, the 666
building. It was 666
um was it on 6th Avenue? I can't."
Anyway, we got caught up in all of that,
you guys. And these were the books that
were pushing this
Watch out for the United Nations
globalism. They're out to destroy
America and American Christianity. And
beloved, it took me some time as I
studied deeper and deeper into our
prophecy. I was like, "Yeah, like no,
yeah, I'm not going to be talking about
this
stuff. This is the actual prophecy." And
yes, there might be, you know, there
might be satanic agencies out there and
people that are worshiping Satan and
blah blah blah, but they have no idea
that whatever they're planning is not
going to come to pass because God has
shown us what is really going to happen
in this world. It's not going to be a
United Nations takeover of the planet.
It's going to be a Christian takeover of
the planet. And it's not going to be
through some organization that's going
to help. It is going to be Satan himself
leading this thing and a world
organization that's going to come and
give America power. That's not how the
prophecy reads. No, that's not how it
reads. So, we need to get out of this
slide. What do you mean? Go ahead. If we
can get out of this slide, I want to go
to the next slide. Yeah. Go ahead. Okay.
So, going back to what I first stated
about the days or the glaze. Could you
hold your thought for a second? If I
hold it, I'm going to forget because
don't forget. Just don't forget it.
Okay. Here's what I want to say. The
United Nations may have bad stuff going
on in it,
just like Jamaica may have bad stuff
going on in Jamaica.
There's bad stuff everywhere.
Bad stuff happening doesn't make it
a Thank you, Ju Julysa. Just hold on.
Let me let me just shed a tear with you
for a moment,
Julysa. Like, praise the Lord. Praise
the Lord. Um, you don't know how many
people out there in Adventism are like
you who may not be willing to even hear
what I'm saying right now. They're just
like, "Nah, you're an apostasy." In
fact, somebody might make a video about
this. Don't be surprised if you see
Pastor Meyer says, "Don't be surprised
because anyway, Jalissa, praise the
Lord, sis. Praise the Lord." Amen. We're
not studying deep enough. We're we're
we're content with
surface seasoned stew.
And I'm telling you, the more I see
Adventists flocking to stew, prophetic
stew, it it just saddens me because I'm
just like, we're supposed to be people
of the book.
How are you How are you saying to me I
am I am ignorant that I cannot see the
United Nations in prophecy and yet not
be able to show me You could show me the
papacy in prophecy. You could show me
apostate problem. How can you not show
me? You can show America and Yeah. How
can you not show me United Nations, but
just say, "Well, it's just there because
we've always said that." No, we haven't
always said that. No, we
haven't. And just the foundation. See,
because I mean, I never hear a lot of
these things because I just don't go and
pay attention. I mean, you're always
gathering what people other people are
saying about things. But um what I was
going to say is when the foundation is
understood the prophecy
correctly. So you're not in a days and
you're not trying to add put 10 on two
or what however that saying goes. It's
like like I was just trying to say
um it's not a world organization or or
the world doesn't come together and then
come comes into America and makes us
join them or or whatever. Do you see
what I'm saying? The prophecy is is that
the power is
here and we clasp
hands with the papal system and it's
going to go around the world and we're
going to get to that. I'm going to show
you why the United N but the whirlwind
is the real kicker. There is going to be
a United Nations, but it's not this
United Nations, you guys. Right. Yeah.
The world, the world is going to I
almost like think the name of the United
Nations like that's it. That's it. The
organization world is going to unite.
No, I mean it's not. It's not. And there
will be a United Nations. Yes. But it's
not this. No.
And I guess I get so whatever about this
is because I four years ago you guys saw
our live about back to the basics. You
saw my the light bulbs go off in my head
like in real time like wow I'm really
really really really getting this. I
can't let that go because it just it
that basic foundational understanding
helps me to understand it gives me the
proper lens to see the rest of the
prophecies and not go off on some crazy
tangent like it's just that doesn't fit
because we're not that doesn't fit we're
not filtering
the the the UN as an evil source is
literally evangelical prophecy which
says they are gathering the whole world
through this
secular global elite satanic
spiritualism.
And so what we do is and you there are
people that actually said to me, "Oh
well the papacy is is uh the first
beast. Uh the um apostate Protestantism
is the second beast and then
spiritualism is the United Nations."
Wow.
So the head of spiritualism is the
United Nations. Well, they have a room
there where they worship Satan in. Hold
on guys, the United Nations is not a
religious organization.
And now I know what some of you are
saying, pastor, you got to read between
the lines. And let me say this, that is
the danger I think that we face as a
people is we keep reading between the
lines while ignoring the actual lines.
When you read in between the lines,
you're able to make up your own stuff.
And even though the lines don't say it,
like you can't go to the United Nations
and see where they say we are an organ
organization that is trying to take over
the world to defeat America. No, it
doesn't say. They're not going to say
that, pastor. But you got to read
between the lines. No, let's stop
reading between the lines and let's
start reading the lines. So that's why
they hate the United Nations because
they think they're going to well so
there's two different I think there's
two different camps. There's
the they're going to try they're trying
to take away Christianity camp, right?
And then they're trying to destroy
America. It's the same thing. Okay.
America is Christianity. Okay. The UN is
global spiritual elites, secular
Marxist, commun.
But again, that doesn't fit. That's
evangel that is evangelical's version of
prophecy and it doesn't fit. So how can
Adventists even adopt that even a little
bit because we all know America is not
going down like that. When you borrow
food from other people mercy and put it
in your
stew, you're going to end up with
something that is not our message at
all. At all. So all these conspiracy
books came out about the UN and then we
start Adventists were reading those
books and the more we read those books
the more we were like yeah you there's
stuff you don't I mean yeah you know
Babylon the prayers of grace papy yeah
but now we're trying
to we're taking all this stuff and
trying to make it a part of our part of
our prophecy
here let's go back to the screen I'm
going to show you something in light of
possible this is from a book called the
glo um shadow government, how the secret
global elite is using surveillance
against you. This is evangelical
writing. Here's what he says. In light
of possible unrestricted nuclear war
between the Soviet Union and the United
States and later China, they formulated
a new international body that came to be
known as the United Nations. What was
announced publicly is that the UN was a
was the global elitist next step in
launching in embriionic form the coming
world government. Members of the Council
on Foreign Relations created after World
War I and still a powerful influence
toward government global government
virtually wrote the UN charter. While
the goal of world peace was laudable,
the unfortunate result was that the
foundation for a global government was
laid without the knowledge or approval
from the citizens of the western nations
that were affected. This is a war
against the west. This is a war against
western ideals against Christianity.
That is an evangelical talking point
that has now been mixed into the stew of
Adventism. M that is not our message.
But we we started reading them. We
started reading those books. We started
talking about that. We started mixing it
into our message. Now let me show you
guys. Ready y'all? I hope y'all are
sitting
down. Let me show you guys um if you
search again in the writings of the
pioneers and look up League of Nations
because the United Nations wasn't
started when our pioneers were still
alive. Mhm. But but while some of them
were still living, there was a League of
Nations. But if you look at this, League
of Nations is mentioned once in the
Ellen White search once. If you now go
to the United Nations, get ready for
this, you guys. Here we go. Here is how
the Adventist Church responded to the
United Nations
um when they were formed. The United
Nations Organization, by the way, you'll
see all my sources at the bottom right
here. The United Nations Organization
may and we fervently hope will tide over
the present at some and subsequent
crises. It may and we hope will long
keep back war from among the nations
that the good news of the gospel may go
to every nation and kindred and tongue
and people. But sooner or later it will
be overwhelmed by the demonic forces
which are d which are driving a doomed
world to destruction and will be
impotent meaning powerless to avert the
final crisis of
history. Let's come back for a moment
when the United Nations is being formed.
This is early
on. The Adventist church's response was,
"Listen, the United Nations, we hope
it's going to do good things, but
eventually it's going to become
powerless because this world is coming
to an end." The United Nations was
formed to avert
war, not to o. So Babylon was overcome
by Meo Persia. Meoersia was overcome by
Greece. Greece was overcome by Rome.
Rome fell into these barbarian tribes.
The formation of the United Nations does
not follow the trend of all the other
nations that came before prophetically,
right? Their goal was world dominion
through war.
The United Nations, whether it is
whether it is good or bad,
I'm not talking about is it good or bad.
I'm simply saying is it prophetic? You
may say all day long, oh there's a lot
of satanic stuff that happens there.
There may be a lot of satanic stuff.
There's a lot of satanic stuff that
happens in every nation. Yes. It doesn't
make it a part of the elements of
prophecy.
In the three angels messages,
so look at what our church is saying.
They're like, we think it eventually is
going to become powerless
to stop what's coming. Let's go back to
the screen. I want you to note
this. This is July 26,
1995. Fear and high
hope. You see the title is the United
Nations the Golden Gate to a better
world. And here we have, get ready for
this you guys, Arthur Maxwell. Now,
Arthur Maxwell bedtime stories, right?
Right. Right. Uh, please. I think some
of y'all are gonna going to go back into
y'all are going to be like, I read
bedtime stories to my children. We did.
I am throwing out bedtime stories. My
kids will never because Arthur Maxwell
was
a Jesuit. Arthur
Maxwell didn't see anything wrong with
the United Nations. Let's read what
Arthur Maxwell says.
He says, "I have um I have just spent
the best part of the week at the United
Nations
um 10th anniversary celebration in San
Francisco. I happened uh I listened to
Eisenhower uh Molotov and they list all
these names and a host of other speakers
and came away with some very definite
impressions." And he goes on, I'm not
I'm not going to take time to read
everything he says. Here's one. Here is
what he concludes. Not for one moment
would I question the motives of the
architects and promoters of this great
organization. Hold on. Wait a minute.
Did author Maxwell just call the United
Nations a great organization? What in
the world? Mhm.
He goes on to say, "Undoubtedly, they
have made a notable contribution to
human welfare and to the improvement of
relationships between the nations, but
I'm concerned that their activities are
outside of and apart from the Christian
program as set forth in the Holy
Scriptures. They are depending for
success upon diplomacy, discussion,
conferences, and treaties to accomplish
their desired end. But in all their
propaganda, so far as I've seen, there
is no mention of any need of conversion
through the grace of Christ, which is
absolutely basic to the Christian
concept of a warless world. Okay, you
guys, Arthur
Maxwell is
not deluded.
He says, "Hey, the United Nations is a
great organization. Their goal is is is
is honorable. They want world peace.
They don't want any more fightings. They
don't want any more Babylon, meet me,
Persia, Greece, Rome. They don't want
any more of this war. So, they are
existing. Their stated purpose of
existing is not to take over the world."
But conspiracy theorists, I could hear
them right now, would say, "That's just
the cover.
Yeah. What they're really doing behind
the lines. And you know what, guys? It's
the reading between the lines. Listen
y'all, when we're teaching about the
papacy, we don't have to read between
the lines. They come out and say
themselves. Yeah. When we're talking
about pro apostate Protestantism, we
don't need to read between the lines.
Listen to me, y'all. It is always
unsafe to put words into somebody's
mouth that they never said. That's what
you call reading between the lines. I
have had people make whole videos about
me, putting words in my mouth that I
never said. And now people going around
saying, "Pastor said this." Ask me, "Go
find a clip where I said that." Well,
you didn't say it. But if you read
between the
lines and that
is what the devil does.
He wants us to read. God doesn't tell us
to read between the lines, right? God t
he lays it out for us. He lays it out
for us in the lines.
So when we're of this at Well, United N
Yeah, they say this, but you got to
read.
Show me where the or the the the United
Nations says. So officially, guys, we
are a satanic organization that plans to
take over Christianity in America.
And guess what? Even if they did say
that, we know that that's not going to
happen. That's not prophecy.
That's speculation.
Y'all don't understand what the Bible
says. The Bible says that things are
going to go down this way. So, let me
keep going. Let's go back to the slides.
And I'm going to just skim through these
quickly, you guys. I'm I will make my
slides available as I usually do. Yes.
But I'm just showing you here's signs of
the time or the Bible in our times 1960.
The United Nations is
undoubtedly one of the forces by means
of which the winds of strife have been
restrained on the
earth. Somebody's about to pass out
right now. I know this is Adventist
literature, you guys.
There is the link. And then they go on
to say, "But we know it's not gonna
last.
We know it's not going to last." Okay.
Um here
is here's another
one.
Um this is Arthur Maxwell actually. May
25th, 1953. Not for a moment would we
question the goodness, the virtue, the
nobility of the men and women who
dreamed this lovely dream. Nor would we
think of scorning the labor of their
devoted hands. Yet we would be recreant
to our trust if we did not declare that
this too shall pass. Like every effort
man has made to save himself in years
gone by. So this latest of his magnifi
of his of his magnificent illusions will
dissolve into a sad and poignant memory.
And he's talking about you see right up
at the top the United Nations. Mhm.
You know they would be stoned today for
saying that. Or see they have this is
evidence that they have sold out to the
UN.
All right.
Here is an entire magazine. This is
Liberty magazine. an entire the entire
this entire uh
um publication this particular
publication the entire thing was do was
dedicated to what the United Nations was
doing there you see the link you can go
and check it out for yourself all right
so these are the responses I was talking
about and I'm not going to I'm not going
to show these responses you could you
know oh wow it froze okay they're
they're they're ivory or not even pastor
anymore. It's just Ivor. This is a lack
of wisdom on your part, my friend.
That's what they're saying to me. Okay.
Um let's go back. Let's go back. So here
you see one that says and some of these
are, you know, some of these are are
well-meaning, right? So one says uh to
claim it is not there when referring to
the UN is to be willfully blind. The UN
is the only global civil structure
capable of enforcing international
religious mandates. Wow. It's not the
religious part. It's the state power
necessary to form the image of the
beast. So, you see, right, there's all
of these reason. Okay. And how you can't
see it, you know, um here's another one
that says um spiritualism, new age
mysticism, occult, charisma of spiritual
manifestations, secular government. All
of these are part of the dragon element.
So, there's the beast, the false
prophet, and the dragon. Pastor, that's
spiritualism. You got to see the UN
note. Now, no verses, just commentary.
Someone said this, "EU seems to be where
we need to look. Here is the artwork
outside the EU, and there's a woman
riding a beast." And that is supposed to
be the evidence. Now, remember y'all,
when we claim to be people of the book,
what we're saying is whatever we teach
prophetically, we can back up from the
Bible. Right? So, that's all I'm asking.
I don't want the seasonings. Right? The
seasonings is look at the picture. I
don't want the
seasonings. I want the foundation. I
want the meat. Then we can add If you're
not seasoning the food, then what are
you adding seasoning to?
Right. Show me the text is what I'm is
what I'm asking.
Um, go ahead. I I just can't like I just
can't stop. I just don't Hold on. I'm
gonna ask you to hold your thought
again. Let me show this slide. I just
want everyone to know. I like what this
person said. I I want you guys to take
note how many times I have cut her off.
Thank you. And I'm I don't I'm not mad
about it either, but I'm just saying
because I usually get blamed for doing
that to him. So, I'm just I want y'all
to pay attention to that. But go ahead.
So, listen to what this person says.
Sometimes we get caught up with so many
current events and we forget that what
the Bible actually says. We SDAs are all
over the place when it comes to prophecy
and current events. I believe that's
exactly what the devil wants. Keep more
focus on the Bible and spirit of
prophecy and you will actually see what
is relevant and what is irrelevant in
current events.
That's I like that. Of course. Yeah. Of
course. This is another person, not the
same one. Someone else said the 10 horns
of Revelations 17 that is the UN
organization. And again, what we have
seen is that that came from Jehovah's
Witnesses. That's what they teach. We
don't teach what they teach. No, we do
not. No, we do not. Go ahead. I cut you
off. Go ahead. It's okay. It's okay. Um,
but I I just, you know, just again
having the foundation and understanding
it. It doesn't allow me to even enter
into this space with this uh because
okay there's there might the United
Nations is a entity. It's a it's a
movement, but there's nothing that they
can do and it may be a movement of bad
people in it, but there's nothing they
can do to bring this whole world
together. And as we learned in back to
the basics, I always say we need to do a
do a new series on it, but bec you know
there there's nothing there's nothing
they can do that can bring the whole
world together except except the
whirlwind. And let's go and let's go to
the screen because that's the very text
I have up now. The world. Wow. And I
didn't even know you're You set that up
nicely. I really didn't know. Listen.
Listen to what the Bible says in Daniel
11:40. At the time of the end shall the
king of the north push at him, and the
king of the south or king of the south
push at him. And the king of the north
shall come against him like a whirlwind,
like with chariots, and with horsemen,
and with many ships, and he shall enter
into the countries, and shall overflow
and pass over. Note verse 41. He shall
enter also into the glorious land and
many countries shall be what?
Overthrown. Yes. Overthrown. Let let me
let me let's come back for a moment. So
we know if you've if you watch the back
to basics series, we know that this
verse ties in with with another verse
we'll look at later, Isaiah 65, which
talks about Jesus coming again like a
whirlwind with fire. Right? We
understand that Daniel 11:40 is the
verse that is telling us about Satan
counterfeiting the coming of Jesus, but
note what it says about the countries.
But don't leave off that
piece, but bringing dead loved ones.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. To me, that's the
biggest piece. Like, yes. Satan um
impersonating Christ. Yes. Of course,
that's huge. But resurrecting the dead,
the dead loved ones, that's the in mass
in mass. That's what Satan need. He
needs that peace. Y You know what I'm
saying? Because he needs that to to pull
on our emotions to Yeah. to override
Yeah. our cognitive thinking.
It's not He needed that. He needs that.
Watch this. It's not the government that
demands
that
demands this mark of the beast. It's the
people.
Yeah. It's not the United Nations, you
guys. Right. It's the people.
The people are convinced. When the text
says that many countries shall be
overthrown, what that's literally saying
is that the way our world is now, it is
going to be different. Every nation is
going to be over the United Nations is
going to be overthrown. America is going
to be overthrown. Let me show you. Let
me show you what what Ellen White says
here. When Protestantism shall stretch
forth her hand across the Gulf to grasp
the hands grasp hands with the Roman
power. When she shall reach over the
abyss to clasp hands with spiritualism
with the UN. When when they shall reach
over the abyss to clasp hands with the
UN. You guys U the UN is not the
spiritualism she's talking about. The
spiritualism that she's talking about is
the appearing of Satan as Jesus.
and dead and dead loved ones. When under
this influence, this three-fold union,
our country shall do what? Repudiate
every principle of his constitution as a
Protestant and republic government.
Meaning the way America is now, it
ceases to be. The country will be
overthrown.
Randcraft has a good question because
you had mentioned it and you never
rewrote the king of the north. He's No,
I have not rewritten the king of the
north yet. He mentioned it after. Yes,
that's something. Then we may know that
the time has come for the marvelous
working of Satan and that the end isn't
near. You guys stop guessing. Stop
climate change. Oh, this here. Oh, this
here. Oh, that there. Oh, the vaccines.
Oh, co. Stop. Let's stop throwing
everything in the pot as part of
prophecy. We don't need to do that. Like
has no power in the world together. We
don't need to do that, you guys. Because
forgive me if I'm sounding passionate
right now and y'all are like, "Oh, why
are like I'm sorry if this is offensive
to you, but I'm not trying to be
offensive you guys. I'm trying to say
you guys, we we have to open our eyes.
It is getting to the point where the
deception may be so deep that you will
not be able to break out of it. Mhm.
Okay.
So, Isaiah
66:15, please note the text. Isaiah
66:15. This is where Satan appears like
Jesus. Or this is the this is how we get
this appearing of Satan like Jesus.
Watch. For behold, the Lord will come
with fire with his chariots like a
whirlwind to render his anger with fury
and his rebuke with flames of fire. This
is exactly what we just read back in
Daniel 11. He will come with a
whirlwind, with chariots, and with
horsemen. How does Jesus come? He will
come uh with fire and his chariots like
a whirlwind. For by fire and by his
sword will the Lord plead with all
flesh. Verse 17, they that sanctify
themselves. Verse 18, for I know their
works. Verse 19, I will set up an end
sign. Verse 20, they shall bring then
and they shall bring all your brethren
for an offering unto the Lord. Verse 21,
I will take of them priests and Levites.
Verse 22, for as a new heavens and a new
earth remain. Verse 23, it shall come to
pass that from one new moon to another
and from one Sabbath to another. Here,
beloved, is the text that is showing
that when
Satan impersonates Christ, the world
will think this is the millennium.
And what does Jesus do in the
millennium? Oh, he's going to make
everyone come worship him from Sabbath
to Sabbath.
Watch this, you guys. Let me go back to
the
screen. Notice what Ellen White says
here. They declared that they had the
truth, that miracles were among them,
that angels from heaven talked with them
and walked with them, that great power
and signs and wonders were performed
among them, and that this was the
temporal millennium which they had been
expecting so long. The whole world was,
what's that word there, Tante?
Converted. The whole world was, what's
the word? Converted. The whole world was
one more time. What's the word?
Converted. Was the whole world
secular? Was the whole world a global
elitist, Marxist, communist, Muslim? No.
The whole world was converted. What are
they saying? This is a temporal
millennium. When does a temporal
millennium begin in their eyes? When
Jesus comes again and angels walk among
them and miracles are being worked among
them. This is the obvious sign that
Jesus is here. It is not the UN that the
devil's going to use to make everybody
worship the be. It is Satan himself
appearing as Jesus. The whole world is
converted.
No more Muslims, no more Buddhists, no
more secularists, no more Marxists, no
more communists, no more atheists, no
more agnostics.
Everybody is converted
except the people who keep the
commandments of God and have the
testimony of Jesus. That is when the
nations unite. Yes. And
Satan doesn't have that power to do
that. Like think about it. If he had the
power to do that, he would do it now.
The re again I'm going to say this
again. The reason why he has to go the
spiritualism route and bring back dead
loved ones, it's the only way to con to
convince people, convince the world.
We're too much at war with each other.
Exactly. Muslims are not going to listen
to the UN say we think because of
because of uh natural disasters that
everybody should worship Jesus on
Sunday. You guys, the Sunday law is not
just about a day off. If a day off was
was was was given today, Sunday is a day
off. That's not the mark of the beast.
The mark of the beast is the forced
worship of Jesus. Is the forced worship
of a Sunday Sabbath, not a Sunday to
chill. It is a religious thing.
And the only way atheists and Muslims
and agnostics and
newagers are going to do this is through
spiritualism, which is not the UN, you
guys. That is
so we're better than that, you guys.
We let's not be we need I think I I
believe as time goes on we need to be so
pinpointed and so accurate in our
prophetic understanding that we cannot
be gained right we don't make stuff up
cut the fat take the take all the stuff
out of the pot that doesn't belong there
that's what I'm trying to say you guys
can I say this go ahead go ahead because
and I've I've told you this many many
many many many many
times that because it's through
spiritualism like Satan again does not
have power on his own. He had to bring
in the spiritualism aspect to be able to
win people
over. I feel like our
focus like like let's just say when we
have an evangelistic series we have one
night on spiritualism.
I I Yeah. Yeah. Yep. I believe this is
me speaking. Okay. This is this is me
speaking. I think that's a huge mistake.
Yeah,
we because people walk away and they're
like, "Oh, the pope, the Catholic
Church." That's true. That those points
are true. But the Pope and the Catholic
Church alone are not able to even bring
the world together. It is through
spiritualism. So the reason why I say
that we should focus on spiritualism
because that is what's going to protect
people when those dead loved ones come
and your emotions are being tugged on.
We both know how difficult that would be
for the loved ones that we have lost.
If you know, if you understand
spiritualism, we will rebuke
those dead loved ones that are really
demons. Yes. And remember what what a
lot of Adventists think is it's one
here, one there. Like, oh, I woke up and
I saw my No, it's an overwhelming,
right? It's the frogs of Egypt, right?
when the frogs came up and three unclean
spirits like frogs going out to to
gather the whole world. It has to be
around the United Nations and be
overwhelming because if if just like
I'll use my father as an example. If my
father just popped up quote unquote
father um who has passed away but it
didn't happen for somebody else. Well,
it would only affect me. It wouldn't
affect the It has to be global. And
everybody has lost someone. Yeah. We've
all been impacted by death. Look at
this. Look, look at GC 588. Here's what
she says.
The line of distinction between
professed Christians and the ungodly is
now hardly distinguishable. Church
members love what the world loves and
are ready to join with them. And Satan
determines to unite them in one body and
thus strengthen his cause by sweeping
all into the ranks of spiritualism.
How's he going to do this? Through the
United Nations. You guys, come on. Let's
think that through. Think about how that
sounds. The devil's going to use the
United Nations to sweep everybody into
spiritualism.
No, no, no, no. Listen to what she says.
Papis who boast of miracles as a certain
sign of the true
church will be readily deceived by this
wonderworking power. And Protestants
having cast away the shield of truth
will also be deluded. Papist,
Protestants and worldling worldlings
will alike accept the form of godliness
without power and they will see in this
union a grand movement for the
conversion of the world and the ushering
in of the long expected millennium.
There she says it again. What is the
long expected millennium? It is when
Jesus comes as Satan. And the ve the
very next sentence
through spiritualism, Satan appears as a
benefactor of the race, healing the
disease of the people and professing to
present a new and more exalted system of
religious faith. But at the same time,
he works as a
destroyer. You cannot make it more
clearer than this. You cannot make it
more clearer than this.
And then I'm sorry, let me read this
last
one. As the crowning act in the great
drama of deception, Satan himself will
personate Christ. The church has long
been has long professed to look to the
Savior's advent as the consummation of
her hopes. Now the great deceiver will
make it appear that Christ has come. In
different parts of the earth, Satan will
manifest himself among men as a majestic
being of dazzling brightness, resembling
the description of the son of God given
by John in the revelation. The glory
that surpasses him is unsurpassed by
anything that mortal eyes have yet
beheld. The shout of triumph rings out
in the air. Christ has come. Christ has
come. The people prostrate themselves in
adoration before him while he lifts up
his hands and pronounces a blessing upon
them as Christ blessed his disciples
when he was upon the earth. His voice is
soft and subdued, yet full of melody. In
gentle, compassionate tones, he presents
some of the same gracious heavenly
truths which the Savior uttered. He
heals the diseases of the
people and then in his assumed character
of Christ claims to have changed the
Sabbath to Sunday and commands all to
hallow the day which he has blessed.
When does a command to hollow the day
come? When Satan himself gives it. And
when he gives it, all the people are
ready to believe it and demand it
because they believe this is Jesus.
Beloved, Satan does not need the United
Nations. No. See, this idea of needing
the United Nations to enforce here's
where here's where that idea comes from.
That idea is like all the Christians of
America are going to be like gunned up,
you know, like, you know, hiding out
while the UN is sending out their forces
and their troops to get the Americans.
You guys, that's evangelical prophecy.
That's not what we believe.
But here we are, which is weak and
basic, which is weak and basic. It's not
true. Here we are mixing that into the
pot.
I'm almost done. I go ahead. You go
ahead and talk. I got a little more to
share and then we're going to be done.
Um I would just I I just want to say
that because it just the thought just
came to me like because the whole world
is deceived on the state of the dead.
Like literally the whole world is
deceived.
atheist,
Muslims, Buddhists, Catholics, Bapt I
mean I don't care what who you are. That
is the one thing that they have no
shield for. Neither Catholics, neither
Protestants, neither the world. So it's
so easy. Absolutely. He already has the
world on that. All he That's why he's
coming with spiritualism because he
already has them right there in the same
space. All he has to do Yeah. is popup
the dead demon loved ones as it so he
already has and that is why I know just
like you're passionate about what you're
passionate about I am so passionate
about this I really believe that this
should be our focus you need to speak
into the mic okay guys this bring you
closer this should be our focus I truly
believe this because this is what
they're going this is what's going to
deceive them so let me say this and I
haven't said this in a while but you
Because this is this is when I realized
I was like, "Yeah, okay. I get it now."
Wow, Tiffany. It is. The
Pope is to
Satan what John the Baptist was to
Jesus.
Yeah. You Yeah. John the Baptist said,
"I am not the
one." But our problem is we have kind of
eliminated Satan out the picture or even
put his appearing after the close of
probation. So, it doesn't really matter.
So all we're focused on
is the papacy,
the pope. What did he do? What did he
do? The pope has no power to convince
the atheist, the skeptic, the Muslim,
the Buddhist, he has no power to
convince them that they should be
worshiping on the first day of the week.
He has no power to do that.
So the if the pope were to say today, I
demand everybody worship. You know what
would happen? World War II,
people would be like, "Why? Why should I
listen to the Pope?"
Right? Like that's why it doesn't matter
who the next pope is. You guys, it
doesn't
take the time that we have now to preach
the message and prepare the people for
the overwhelming delusion that is coming
that will happen without warning. Mhm.
There is no sign. Which is why I say
over and over again, that's why all 10
virgins are sleeping when this thing
happens because nobody knows when it's
coming, right? It's not something you
could look out for and say, "Oh, I think
the devil is about to do his thing now
because this and this and this
happened."
So, I got one more thing to share and
then we'll wrap this up. Okay? So we
know the United Nations isn't in Daniel
2 because the toes of iron and clay
is is church craft and state craft. It
is the uniting of the whole world. It is
not about the United Nations
organization.
Do I've never heard anybody any of our
evangelists preach the United Nations
organization from Daniel chapter 2. So
it's not there. It's not in Daniel 7.
It's not in Daniel 11. All right, let's
go over to Revelation. It's not in
Revelation chapter 13. It's not in
Revelation chapter 12. It's not in
Revelation 11. Some say, "Oh, well, what
about Revelation chapter 17?" So, let's
go. Let's go to Revelation chapter
17. And um I'm going to put the verse up
on the screen. Here's the verse that
people
suggest. They're not saying this is
it. They're saying, "Oh, maybe it's
here." And the t horns which thou sawest
are 10 kings which have received no
kingdom as yet. but receive power as
kings, one earth with the beast. These
have one mind and shall give their power
and strength unto the
beast.
So I just want you to see uh see what
sister White says right here on this and
we can do this from the Bible but I just
want to show you just so that you can
see very quickly. In the 17th of
Revelation is foretold the destruction
of all the
churches who corrupt themselves by
idolatrous devotion to the service of
the papacy. Those who have drunk of the
wine of the wrath of her fornication.
Huh? Notice how she used the word
churches.
Churches. Here's what she says. Thus is
represented the paper. Oh. So then um
John writes and she quotes Revelation 17
1-4. And then she says, "Thus is
represented the papal power which with
all deceivleness of unrighteousness by
outside attraction and gorgeous display
deceives all nations, promising them, as
did Satan, our first parent, all good to
those who receive its mark, and all harm
to those who oppose its
fallacies." The power which has the
deepest inward corruption will make the
greatest display, and will clothe itself
with the most elaborate signs of power.
The Bible plainly declares that this
cover up that this cover is a corrupt
and deceiving wickedness. Upon her
forehead is written the name Babylon,
mother of harlots. Then she says this,
"What is that? What is it that gives its
kingdom to this power?" So now she's
just come back. Come back to me for a
second. Come back for a
second. She's asking the question, what
is it that gives its kingdom to this
power? M because in Revelation chapter
17 it says these 10 horns reign with
this with uh with uh this power for you
know an hour. They give their strength
and power onto it. So she's asking the
question who are these 10 horns and I
want you to notice what she says you
guys. So you said you know that game was
the prices right where they say survey
says is it survey you remember that
surve Yeah. Yeah. survey says I don't
know if that's price and they'll go ding
and you see the sign come up. No, that's
um that's family feud. No, no, no.
Family feud is right. No price family.
It doesn't matter. It doesn't matter.
Where where they turn the letters. Yeah.
Yeah. They see what people say and then
service and it's family feud. Family
feud. Yeah. So many of you said Price is
right about prices. Yeah. Many of you
said nations.
The United Nations. That's who the T
horns are. That's who gives it power and
strength to the beast.
Please note what she says here. It is
family feud. It is family feud. Ready
for the ding, you guys? Here it goes.
First of all, United Nations is
incorrect. It is not there. What is the
answer? Let's read it. Put it up on the
screen. What is it that gives its
kingdom to this power? Protestantism.
A power which while professing to have
the temper and spirit of a lamb and to
be alive to heaven speaks with the voice
of a dragon, it is moved by a power from
beneath.
Wow. Wow. Wow. Wow. Protestantism. You
know what that tells me? That tells me
that the whole world will be converted
to Christianity.
Just as we read just a little while ago,
the whole world will be
converted to follow Jesus.
I know what many of you may be thinking
right now. But what about all the books
and all the juicy stuff that we got from
those books? You mean we can't talk
about the UN anymore? You could talk
about the UN all you want. I I'm not
saying don't talk about the UN. I'm just
saying do not present it as part of our
prophecy. Yes. And if you want to go off
on stuff that is not a part of our
prophecy, you know, if you want to pay
attention to things that don't matter,
if you have energy for that, no, I no,
don't pay attention to that. Pay
attention to Jesus and the truth and our
correct prophecies. Learn them properly.
Do not let a a just a glaze go over your
mind. Be able to teach it um to others
so that they can understand. be able to
teach people the truth about the state
of the dead. I mean, like, and tie it in
with the prophecy so they can understand
they don't want to be deceived. Stop
eating prophecy stew, right? And I know
what's going to happen like, you know,
many people like this, wait a minute,
United Nations has to be in, well, if
United Nations is where where you all
think it is, then the Jehovah's
Witnesses were right and the
evangelicals are right. And how come
Ellen God didn't give Ellen White this
vision?
How come how come she didn't see that uh
there would be a uniting of a certain uh
you know system of nations that would
assist the papacy in doing x y and z.
So my belief you guys and we're going to
end on this note is that Satan is simply
trying to distract the church in any way
that he can in any way. And one of the
ways that I think in which he's doing it
now which is we will close on this point
is that the church is not the church.
One more question I want to answer. One
more thing I want to deal with is the
church is not the organization. The
church is actually the people and there
are people going around saying this and
doing all kinds of you know here's the
evidence that and there's a statement
that they're using. I'm going to put the
state up statement up on the screen and
then we'll we'll close. We're just going
to do this very quickly.
So look at this. Let's go to the screen.
Let's go to the screen. Um, and uh, here
we go. God has a church. It is not the
great
cathedral. Adventists don't have
cathedrals.
Neither is it the national
establishment. Neither is it the various
denominations. I don't think she was
saying here. Some people are taking this
to say that the denomination of seventh
day Adventism is what she's talking
about, including this in this statement.
She's not talking about Adventism in
this statement. She's talking about the
various denominations which make up
mystery Babylon.
It goes on to say, "It is the people who
love God and keep his commandments."
Well, who are they? Well, they are the
people who make up the Seventh Day
Adventist Church. Mhm. So to say that
the church is really where two or three
people are gathered, which it is. And
that means that the church is not the
organization is is absolute fallacy.
It's it's
it's putting something into the
statement that is not there. You cannot
say, "Oh, the church is the people,
right? But it's not the system." No, the
church is the people and it's the
system. God has always had an
organization. Mhm. When he when he when
he called the children of Israel out of
Egypt in the Old Testament, he created
an organized church. He gave them a
system of how to do things. There was a
temple or there was a system. In the New
Testament, God gave the New Testament
church a system and that's why they had
the council of Jerusalem. There was a
system and there was order. So God has
an order church. During the dark ages
when the church was scattered, Yeah. the
woman was in the wilderness. There was
no system. it was the people. But after
coming out of Babylon in 1844, God has a
system again. That's what 1844 is all
about. God has an organization on
church. So to say that God does not have
an organization on church,
the next step will be the church is
Babylon, right? It's not you won't say
that yet. But you're setting yourself up
to then say the organization is Babylon
and the organization can be Babylon
because the real church is the people.
Let me read one statement here and then
we'll wrap this up. She says here uh two
statements, I'm sorry. She says, "Yet
the feeling against organizations
um was very strong among our people. The
Adventists generally who had who had
withdrawn from the churches of the
various denominations." There goes that
term again. Various denominations under
the call of the second angel's message
to come out of Babylon opposed
organization. No, no, no, no, no. That's
organization is Babylon. We don't want
to
organize. And manyday Adventists were
fearful that church organization would
bring us under condemnation. We sought
the Lord with earnest prayer that we
might understand his will. and light was
given to us by his spirit that there
must be order and thorough discipline in
the church that organization was
essential.
You
guys listen if we can here's my here's
my fear and you can you can you can be
the organization that God has called and
still you're not that's ran by human
beings so it's not going to be perfect.
That's right. Because human beings are
not perfect. Israel was not perfect. Was
there corruption in the church in the
wilderness?
Yes, there was. Was there corrup is
there corrupt? Would there be cor?
Because there's going to be corruption
with the people if there was no
organization because we're human.
Period. And we'd probably be I'll be
honest. If there was no
structure, we would be worse. would be
worse because without any structure and
the human beings just do their own
thing. Do their own thing without any
structure, any guidance. Yeah, it would
be worse. Yeah. Listen to what she says
here. Listen what I just got. Five
minutes and we're done. Okay. Five
minutes and we're done. Said that three
times. I didn't say five minutes. You
never said five minutes. Now I'm saying
five minutes. He's winding cuz I
literally have He's winding. He's
getting close. Yeah. See? One. He's
getting close. Two. Three. Four. Yep.
Here we go. Killer way past my bedtime.
I know. I'm sorry. He thrives in the
night. I thrive in the morning. Here's
what she
says.
Now, we can expect that a message would
be
true that would designate I'm sorry.
Now, can we expect that a message would
be true that would designate as Babylon
the people for whom God has done so
much? In other words, yeah. Yeah. Maybe
not the people, but the system is
Babylon.
Hell would triumph were such a message
to be received and the world would be
strengthened in iniquity. All the
reproaches which Satan has cast upon the
character of God would appear as truth
and the conclusion would be made that
God has no chosen or organized church in
the world. Oh, what a triumph this would
be to Satan and his confederacy of evil.
God does not work in this way. He does
not just he does not he does just what
he said he would do in the 58th chapter
of Isaiah. Let me keep reading. Has God
no living church? He has a church but it
is not the church
militant or but it is the church
militant not the church triumphant. We
are sorry that there are defective
members that there are tears amid the
wheat. Jesus said and she quotes the
whole parable of the tears and the
wheat. She goes on to say, "In the
parable of the wheat and the tears, we
see the reason why the tears were not to
be plucked up. It was less the wheat
should be uprooted with the tears. Human
opinion and judgment would make grave
mistakes." But rather than have a
mistake made and one single blade of
wheat rooted up, the master says, "Let
both grow unto the harvest." Listen you
guys, I know I know that there is
corruption in our church from the
bottom, from the churches all the way to
the top. I know that. How do I know
that? Not because I have some inside
information, but because Jesus said the
wheat and the tears would grow together.
He also said, "Do not uproot the wheat
or the the tears, lest you also uproot
the wheat." Right now, is this to say
that you don't try to correct things
that you see are wrong? No. That's not
what is being said at all. What is being
said, though, is that God's church is
still his church regardless
of the human corruption that is in it.
And it's his church because of the
truth. because the truth not because of
the people. Right? There is only one
system on earth that has the system of
truth and that is the remnant church. In
that system of truth, there is a lot of
error in the hearts of people. Yes,
there is a lot of antagonism in the
hearts of people. There are people who
are willing to step on others and put
others down so they can raise themselves
up. There are ministries that do this.
Trust me, it doesn't make God's church
Babylon. It doesn't make God's church no
longer his church. And God gave us the
example of Israel. That's right. So that
we could see, okay, even when God has a
church, it's a whole lot of mess that
can go on, but it was still his church.
That's right. Until it wasn't. And why
was it not his church anymore? Because
they rejected the truth. Right. Right.
They rejected Jesus.
And in rejecting Jesus, they no longer
had the truth.
The church is the church because it is a
system of truth, right? It's not the
church because everybody in it is good
and pure and holy and right and doing
what you think it ought to be done right
and everybody is this way in heaven.
It's not that that it's the the church
militant is God's church right now. It
will eventually be the church
triumphant, but we're not the ones that
make it the church triumphant. Okay, I'm
done. Um, to me that was its own that
could be its own discussion. It own
discussion and you just used it. So to
close off, but definitely could be its
own discussion. So please put a one in
the chat if you if you learned something
tonight. Put a one in the chat if you
were blessed tonight. Um,
I learned something just by by
discussing this again and fleshing some
things out. Some I feel like the Holy
Spirit brought some things to my mind
that I hadn't thought of before. For
sure. Yeah. My appeal is this, you guys.
Number one, stay on the ship. That's
right. Number
two, throw overboard the stuff that
doesn't belong on the ship, right?
Because it's weighing the ship down.
It's weighing the ship down, but the
ship will not sink. But the ship isn't
going to sink. Get rid of prophecy stew.
Just say no more prophecy stew for me.
No more prophecy stew.
Listen y'all, the people that are giving
prophecy stew and feeding prophecy stew,
when when it Oh, that didn't happen.
That didn't happen. Mhm. It's almost
like we just blink the eye and keep
moving on. What's next?
It's almost like a drug addict or drug
dealer dealing drugs to a drug addict.
I Hey, I know you want your fix. You
keep coming to me and providing
business. I will keep giving you the
fix. Right. I will keep You keep coming
to me for the drug. I will keep giving
you the dopamine. Well, this one didn't
work. Yeah, but you know what? This one
is better. Right.
I got to get my head,
you guys. Let's stop.
Let's be accurate with our with our
understanding of prophecy. Let's be
accurate. No more prophecy stool.
Let's get rid of the cha the
chaff. Let's study our Bibles. Yes.
Let's study our Bibles. Done. Yes. Um,
thank you. I enjoyed it. I will let you
close off. And yes, please, if you
joined um in the middle of this study,
please go back and start at the
beginning once it's done. I mean when
you have time um at some point but if
you have not subscribed to the power of
the lamb channel please do so because uh
you will uh and like please like uh this
this session because you will get uh
notifications when we go live with
topics like this. Um, so please do that.
And again, Living Mana Church and Power
of the Lamb are two separate entities.
So you might be following us at Living
Mana Church, which is wonderful, and
we're thankful that you are there, too.
But Power of the Lamb is is different.
So, um, if you're wanting to get Power
of the Lamb information, you'll need to
subscribe to Power of the Lamb. But with
that said, we want to invite you to
church tomorrow. Um, Living Mana Online
Church. If you enjoyed what you uh heard
uh this evening, you will definitely be
blessed at Living Mana Church tomorrow.
And that starts at 12:00 p.m. Central
Standard Time. And you can Living Mana
Church um YouTube channel to be able to
view that. And my sermon tomorrow will
be when no man can buy or sell.
So I think you will not want to miss
that. You don't want to miss. Yes. Well,
this definitely was a blessing. Would
you like to close? All right. I knew you
were gonna say that because you've been
doing all the talking. Okay. Bow your
heads with me, please. Heavenly Father,
Lord, I just thank you um just for this
study tonight. I I was not going to
join. I decided to join like 40 minutes
before we were going live. And I am so
thankful that I did because for myself,
it helped uh me to understand things in
a more clearer way. And so, I pray that
prayer for everyone who is viewing. And
I pray that they will go and study this
for themselves and they will not um have
any more prophecy stew that uh they are
promoting to others or even for
themselves. Lord, your your word is so
very clear and the truth in the in the
basic of the of our real prophecies is
just it's just it's right there and we
don't need to add anything onto it. We
need to share that with the world. And
so we ask all of these things in Jesus
name. Amen. Amen. Amen. Have a good
evening and hope to see you um tomorrow.
I want to say the morning, but it's not
the morning for everybody.